<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brad Stieber</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Brad Stieber</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>bgstieber@gmail.com (Brad Stieber)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>bgstieber@gmail.com (Brad Stieber)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using R to Create Custom Color Palettes for Tableau</title>
      <link>/post/using-r-to-create-custom-color-palettes-for-tableau/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>bgstieber@gmail.com (Brad Stieber)</author>
      <guid>/post/using-r-to-create-custom-color-palettes-for-tableau/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wanted to define custom color palettes in Tableau, but didn’t know how? In this post, I’m going to walk through how we can use R to programmatically generate custom palettes in Tableau. Creating custom color palettes for Tableau has never been easier!
This is going to be a short post, with just a little bit of R code.
At the end of the post, you’ll see how to use R to generate custom color palettes to add to Tableau.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iterating on a 2016 Election Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/iterating-on-a-2016-election-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>bgstieber@gmail.com (Brad Stieber)</author>
      <guid>/post/iterating-on-a-2016-election-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Jake Low wrote a really interesting piece that presented a few data visualizations that went beyond the typical 2016 election maps we’ve all gotten used to seeing.
I liked a lot of things about Jake’s post, here are three I was particularly fond of:
His color palette choicesEach color palette that was used had solid perceptual properties and made sense for the data being visualized (i.e. diverging versus sequential)He made residuals from a model interesting by visualizing and interpreting themHe explained the usage of a log-scale transformation in an intuitive way, putting it in terms of the data set being used for the analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything I Know About Machine Learning I Learned from Making Soup</title>
      <link>/post/everything-i-know-about-machine-learning-i-learned-from-making-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>bgstieber@gmail.com (Brad Stieber)</author>
      <guid>/post/everything-i-know-about-machine-learning-i-learned-from-making-soup/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionIn this post, I’m going to make the claim that we can simplify some parts of the machine learning process by using the analogy of making soup. I think this analogy can improve how a data scientist explains machine learning to a broad audience, and it provides a helpful framework throughout the model building process.
Relying on some insight from the CRISP-DM framework, my own experience as an amateur chef, and the well-known iris data set, I’m going to explain why I think that the soup making and machine learning connection is a pretty decent first approximation you could use to understand the machine learning process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golf, Tidy Data, and Using Data Analysis to Guide Strategy</title>
      <link>/post/golf-tidy-data-and-using-data-analysis-to-guide-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>bgstieber@gmail.com (Brad Stieber)</author>
      <guid>/post/golf-tidy-data-and-using-data-analysis-to-guide-strategy/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionI’m going to use this post to discuss some of the aspects of data science that interest me most (tidy data as well as using data to guide strategy). I’ll be discussing these topics through the lens of a data analysis of results from a few high school golf tournaments.
I’m going to take a little bit of time to talk about tidy data. When I scraped the data used for this analysis, it wasn’t really stored in a tidy format, and there’s a good reason for that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to the kmeans Algorithm</title>
      <link>/post/an-introduction-to-the-kmeans-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>bgstieber@gmail.com (Brad Stieber)</author>
      <guid>/post/an-introduction-to-the-kmeans-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>This post will provide an R code-heavy, math-light introduction to selecting the \(k\) in k means. It presents the main idea of kmeans, demonstrates how to fit a kmeans in R, provides some components of the kmeans fit, and displays some methods for selecting k. In addition, the post provides some helpful functions which may make fitting kmeans a bit easier.
kmeans clustering is an example of unsupervised learning, where we do not have an output we’re explicitly trying to predict.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>/post/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>bgstieber@gmail.com (Brad Stieber)</author>
      <guid>/post/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog!I plan to use this website to present data explorations and analyses in a way that’s understandable to a broad audience. I hope to demonstrate the utility of applying ideas like machine learning, data visualization, and exploratory data analysis to day-to-day life to improve decision-making processes.
I was inspired to create a blog after reading this post by David Robinson.
New blog post: &amp;quot;Advice to aspiring data scientists: start a blog&amp;quot; https://t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>bgstieber@gmail.com (Brad Stieber)</author>
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Work: I currently work as a Data Analyst in the higher ed / non profit sector. Prior to that, I worked in analytics and reporting for a private financing company. On the side, I am a volunteer data scientist for a few different organizations.
Education: I graduated with an MS in Statistics from the University of Wisconsin in 2017 (go Badgers! 👐). Prior to that, I graduated with a BS in Mathematical Statistics and Mathematical Economics from St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogroll</title>
      <link>/blogroll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>bgstieber@gmail.com (Brad Stieber)</author>
      <guid>/blogroll/</guid>
      <description>Blogs I’m reading:R-bloggers - Blog aggregator of content contributed by bloggers who write about R (in English).
Revolutions - Blog dedicated to news and information of interest to members of the R community.
Statistical Modeling, Causal Inference, and Social Science
eagereyes - Robert Kosara’s website, mostly about data visualization
Julia Silge’s blog - Great blog about a wide array of data science topics
Variance Explained - David Robinson’s (the data scientist, not the basketball player) blog on data science.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>